var quiz = [
    {   question: "10-1",
        correctAnswer: "signal weak",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-2",
        correctAnswer: "signal good",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-3",
        correctAnswer: "stop transmitting",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-4",
        correctAnswer: "affirmative",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-5",
        correctAnswer: "undefined",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-6",
        correctAnswer: "verbal communication only",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-7",
        correctAnswer: "out of service",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-8",
        correctAnswer: "in service",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-9",
        correctAnswer: "repeat",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-10",
        correctAnswer: "negativee",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-11",
        correctAnswer: "suspicious property",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-12",
        correctAnswer: "stand by",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-13",
        correctAnswer: "child abuse",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-14",
        correctAnswer: "message",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-15",
        correctAnswer: "larceny from auto",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-16",
        correctAnswer: "undefined",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-17",
        correctAnswer: "enroute",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-18",
        correctAnswer: "urgent",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-19",
        correctAnswer: "animal control",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-20",
        correctAnswer: "location",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-21",
        correctAnswer: "call at",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-22",
        correctAnswer: "disregard",
        choices: [ "enroute", "stand-by", "affirmative", "disregard"],
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-23",
        correctAnswer: "arrived at scene",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-24",
        correctAnswer: "assignment completed",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-25",
        correctAnswer: "meet me at",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-26",
        correctAnswer: "eta",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-27",
        correctAnswer: "license information",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-28",
        correctAnswer: "registration information",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-29",
        correctAnswer: "wanted check",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-30",
        correctAnswer: "vehicle recovery",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-31",
        correctAnswer: "pick up property",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-32",
        correctAnswer: "fireworks",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-33",
        correctAnswer: "help me quick",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-34",
        correctAnswer: "fraud",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-35",
        correctAnswer: "zone check",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-36",
        correctAnswer: "undefined",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-37",
        correctAnswer: "trespassing",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-38",
        correctAnswer: "911 hangup",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-39",
        correctAnswer: "css needed",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-40",
        correctAnswer: "fight",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-41",
        correctAnswer: "beginning tour of duty",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-42",
        correctAnswer: "ending tour of duty",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-43",
        correctAnswer: "vehicle pursuit",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-44",
        correctAnswer: "protest civil disorder",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-45",
        correctAnswer: "bomb threat",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-46",
        correctAnswer: "alarm residential",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-47",
        correctAnswer: "alarm commercial",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-48",
        correctAnswer: "alarm from vehicle",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-49",
        correctAnswer: "lake enforcement activity",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-50",
        correctAnswer: "accident property damage",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-51",
        correctAnswer: "traffic violation not dui",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-52",
        correctAnswer: "accident with injury",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-53",
        correctAnswer: "road obstruction",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-54",
        correctAnswer: "hit and run",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-55",
        correctAnswer: "intoxicated driver",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-56",
        correctAnswer: "intoxicated person",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-57",
        correctAnswer: "noise disturbance",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-58",
        correctAnswer: "direct traffic",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-59",
        correctAnswer: "escort",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-60",
        correctAnswer: "suspicious vehicle",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-61",
        correctAnswer: "kidnapping",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-62",
        correctAnswer: "b/e residential",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-63",
        correctAnswer: "undefined",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-64",
        correctAnswer: "b/e business",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-65",
        correctAnswer: "armed robbery business",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-66",
        correctAnswer: "armed robbery person",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-67",
        correctAnswer: "deceased person",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-68",
        correctAnswer: "misc vice activities",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-69",
        correctAnswer: "reported suicide",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-70",
        correctAnswer: "parking problem",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-71",
        correctAnswer: "check welfare",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-72",
        correctAnswer: "transport prisoner",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-73",
        correctAnswer: "mental patient",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-74",
        correctAnswer: "confirmed wanted",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-75",
        correctAnswer: "drug related",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-76",
        correctAnswer: "prowler",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-77",
        correctAnswer: "assist other agency",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-78",
        correctAnswer: "lost articles",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-79",
        correctAnswer: "injured person",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-80",
        correctAnswer: "fire/arson report",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-81",
        correctAnswer: "code at the airport",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-82",
        correctAnswer: "meet complainant",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-83",
        correctAnswer: "missing person",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-84",
        correctAnswer: "traffic control malfunction",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-85",
        correctAnswer: "damage to property",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-86",
        correctAnswer: "larceny",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-87",
        correctAnswer: "larceny of vehicle",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-88",
        correctAnswer: "suspicious person",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-89",
        correctAnswer: "reckless driver",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-90",
        correctAnswer: "assault no weapon",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-91",
        correctAnswer: "domestic problem",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-92",
        correctAnswer: "assault with weapon",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-93",
        correctAnswer: "verbal confrontation",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-94",
        correctAnswer: "armed subject",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-95",
        correctAnswer: "sexual assault",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-96",
        correctAnswer: "disabled vehicle",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-97",
        correctAnswer: "animal problem",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-98",
        correctAnswer: "school violation",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
    {   question: "10-99",
        correctAnswer: "serve warrant/warrant on file",
        usersAnswer: "",
    },
];






// array for holding the answers choose from in the dom
var allAnswersArray = [];
function getIndexes() {
    for (var i = 0; i < quiz.length; i++) {
        allAnswersArray.push(quiz[i].correctAnswer);
    };
};

getIndexes();
// console.log(allAnswersArray);
//----------------------------





//--------------variables -----------
var selected;
var haveSelected = false;

var num = new Array();
var randomIndexArray = [];

// use tempGameArray to push the questions asked into along with answer guessed
// clear the "tempGameArray" upon reset;
var tempGameArray = [];


// var index = Math.floor(Math.random() * quiz.length - 1);
// console.log(index);
var index = 0;
var arrayIndex = quiz[index];  // this will be the array with index
var objectForArray = new Object();  // this will be the object pushed to the temp array each question

function displayQuestion(index) {
    var x = quiz[index];
    // console.log(x);
    console.log("this is the answer: "+ x.correctAnswer);
    console.log("question: " + x.question);

    // push the selected answer and question to tempGameArray
    // var objectForArray = new Object();
    objectForArray.question = x.question;
    objectForArray.correctAnswer = x.correctAnswer;
    // tempGameArray.push(objectForArray);
    // console.log("belowis the new temp array");
    // console.log(tempGameArray);
    console.log(objectForArray)

    //==================================
    $(".display-question").text(x.question);

    for (i = 0; i < 3; i++) {
        num[i] = Math.floor(99 * Math.random());
        if (num[1] == num[0]) {
            while (num[1] == num[0]) {
                num[1] = Math.floor(99 * Math.random());
            };
        };

        if (num[2] == num[1] || num[2] == num[0]) {
            while (num[2] == num[1] || num[2] == num[0]) {
                num[2] = Math.floor(99 * Math.random());
            };
        };
        // console.log(num[i])
        var j = num[i];
        // console.log("this is J: " + j);
        randomIndexArray.push(allAnswersArray[j]);
        // console.log("answers array: " + randomIndexArray);
    };

    // add the correct answer to the array, randomIndexArray
    randomIndexArray.push(x.correctAnswer);

    // put the random .sort() here ==============

    randomIndexArray.sort(function(a, b){return 0.5 - Math.random()});
    // console.log("this should have a random index: " + randomIndexArray);

    //=============================================

    // this loop put the answers to select from in the dom
    // for (var i = 0; i < 4; i++) {
    //     // console.log("");
    //     var answers = randomIndexArray[i];
    //     $("#selection" + i).text(answers);
    // };

    // create radio buttons and populate with random answers
    for (var i = 0; i < 4; i++) {
        var answers = randomIndexArray[i];
        $("#selection-area").append("<input type='radio' class='radio-button' onclick='radioBtnVal(this.value)' name='questions' value='"+answers+"' text='" + answers + "'>").append("<span> " + answers + "</span>").append("<br>");

        // var radioBtn = $("<input/>");
        // radioBtn.attr("type", "radio").attr("class", "radio-button").attr("name", "questions").attr("value", answers);
        // radioBtn.attr("onclick", "radioBtnVal(this.value)").text(answers);
        // $("#selection-area").append(radioBtn);
    };

   
    // index++;
    //===============================

};


displayQuestion(index);

function radioBtnVal(x) {
    $("#display-selected").text(x);
    selected = x;
    // console.log(selected);
    haveSelected = true;

};

$("#submit-button").on("click", function () {
    if (haveSelected) {
        haveSelected = false;
        console.log("this is selected: " + selected);

// push the selected answer and question to tempGameArray
// var objectForArray = new Object();
// objectForArray.question = x.question;
// objectForArray.correctAnswer = x.correctAnswer;
// objectForArray.selectedAnswer = selected;
// tempGameArray[index].push(selectedAnswer = selected);
objectForArray.selectedAnswer = selected;
console.log(objectForArray);
// tempGameArray.push(objectForArray);
tempGameArray.push(objectForArray);
// console.log("belowis the new temp array");
console.log(tempGameArray);
index++;

//==================================


        // arrayIndex.usersAnswer = selected;
     
        // console.log(quiz);
        // $('.radio-button').attr('checked', false);
        $("#selection-area").empty();
        displayQuestion(index);

    } else {
        console.log("nope");
        alert("Please make a selection");
    }


});


